MDWA Manu Life Dynamic Walth Assurance
Savings or Endowment insurance.  This
is a Manulif product launched
in November 2025.
Please read the disclaimer
first.
Endomen insurance.  Before I explain
about MDWA, I will first explain
what endowment insurance is.
Officially translated as
dual-purpose insurance or two benefits, namely
life protection and savings.  But
actually the main benefit is
savings.
Derived from the word to endow, meaning
to provide provisions or provide
definite funds in the future.
Life insurance is usually small or a
maximum of the same as the savings benefit
and sometimes no UP is
provided at once.
Generally provides savings benefits
in the form of annual installments.
Similar to term savings.   It is
usually marketed as an
education fund or pension fund product or
flexibly for any savings.
Generally simple underwriting or even
without health screening.
is a
very conservative investment instrument.  The returns are
low, roughly equivalent to
deposits or slightly higher.
Low risk, tax free.  Not liquid
while the contract is still running, but
liquid when inherited.
Upper middle class to
HNW segment, high network as
asset diversification and legacy planning.  This is a little
information about endowment insurance or
I prefer to call it
savings insurance.  Because the main benefit is
savings.  If you want to save on
insurance, then this is the place.
Manulif Dynamic Walet Assurance.  Maintain
whatever your financial goals are in the
future.  Education funds, retirement,
inheritance, and wealth accumulation.
MDWA has the tagline safe with MDWA.
There are three plans here.  There are annuity plans
that provide stable cash flow for
retirement, scholarship plans that ensure
children's education funds according to their level, and
combo plans.  Financial security for
these various needs is for savings
in general.  Next is a
brief explanation of MDWA plans and
features.  There are three plans here.
Annuity plans, scholarships, and combo plans.
Annuity plans provide
annual cash payment benefits but do not provide
end-of-term benefits.  The
scholarship plan does not provide
annual cash payment benefits, but only
provides benefits at the end of the
coverage period.  Meanwhile, the combo plan
combines two benefits.  There are
annual cash payment benefits and
end of term benefits.  For the
coverage period, the annuity plan
only has two options, namely 20 and 30
years.  The scholarship plan provides a
coverage period of between 5 to 15 years,
then 20 years and 30 years.  Meanwhile, the
combo plan provides a coverage period of
10, 15, 20 or 30 years.  The
premium payment period for all three is the same, namely
providing three options.  There are premiums for
5 years and 10 years at once.  The
entry age for the premium payment period is 10
years, the entry age is 30 days to 70
years.  The premise payment period
and entry age are 30 days to
85 years.  The currencies are Rupiah and US
Dollar.  The minimum premium for the
lump sum premium payment period is IDR 50
million for rupiah or 5,000 for US.
For a 5 or 10 year premium payment period, the
minimum premium is IDR 24 million in
rupiah or 2,400 US per year.
Basic insurance benefits in the event of death
due to an accident or
permanent total disability.
Additional annual cash benefits are provided every
year until the end of the insurance period.
There are riders or additional insurance
options, one advance life
protector plus 2 manual wavers of premium
plus and manifest benefit plus.
Gio underwriting method is guaranteed offering
or full underwriting if adding a
rider.  So there is a guarantee that the policy will be approved
if there is no rider and if you add a
rider there is full underwriting.  Full
underwriting includes
health questions and may require a
medical test.  But the basic product
is guaranteed to be approved or without
underwriting.  Okay, next the
featured feature can choose cash benefits.
can be staged funds only, final benefits
only, or staged funds plus
final benefits.  These are the three plans earlier, yes.
Premiums can be paid in 5
or 10 years at once.  Provides
coverage periods ranging from 5 to 15 years,
20 years, and 30 years.
Entry age up to 85 years.  This is the one
for single premium.
Policy warranty approved.  Even if you are
seriously ill, you can still participate.
Rupiah and US Dollar currencies.
All benefits are guaranteed and tax-free.
Well, this is one advantage of
endowment insurance and also insurance products in
general that provide savings benefits, the
benefits are guaranteed, the
cash value is guaranteed and it is tax-free.  no need to
pay taxes anymore.
This product can be supplemented with three
additional insurances to expand the scope of
protection.
We see that the MDWA annuity plan is
intended for the preparation and management of
retirement funds.
Provides annual cash payment benefits
with values ​​depending on the
payment period, coverage period, and
premium amount.
Coverage period of 20 and 30 years.
without end of term benefits.
Annual payment benefits are provided
starting from the end of the sixth year for a
lump sum premium or starting from the end of the 10th year
for a 5-year MPP or starting from the end of the
15th year for a 10-year MPP and so on
every year until the end of the
selected coverage period.
This is a table of Tunan payment benefits
for a 20-year coverage period.
Please take a look.  Here there is a
premium payment period of 5 years
or 10 years at once given at the end of the
policy year.  Then the amount of annual payment benefits
is IDR and US Do.  There is a
lump sum premium starting from IDR 50 million or US DO
R5,000.  And for the annual basic premium
starting from IDR 24 million or 2,400 US.  Here are
the benefits.  And for a lump sum premium of IDR
500 million or above or IDR 50,000,000 or
above or for an annual basic premium
starting from IDR 100 million or IDR 10,000, these are
the benefits.  You don't have to memorize this
, it will be in the illustration later.  Furthermore, the
annual cash payment benefit is for a
coverage period of 30 years.  Please take
a look.  Then next is the MDWA
scholarship plan
aimed at preparing
education funds for children or grandchildren.  Why grandchildren?
Because there is a 30 year coverage period,
right?
provides end-of-term benefits
with a value depending on the
payment period, coverage period, and
premium amount.
Does not provide
annual cash payment benefits.
Coverage period 5 to 15 years, 20
years, and 30 years.
This is the MDWA scholarship plan benefits table.   There
are only final benefits here.
Please take a look.  This is for a
lump sum premium starting from IDR 50 million or 5,000 US
or an annual basic premium starting from IDR 24 million
or 2,400 US.  For a coverage period of
5 to 9 years, this only applies to
single premiums.  Meanwhile, for 10
years and beyond, it can be a
lump sum premium or a 5-year premium.
Please see the
table for the basic
lump sum premium starting from IDR 500 million or 50,000
or for the annual basic premium starting from IDR
100 million or 10,000 US.  Please
take a look, no need to memorize it.
Furthermore, the MDWA plan combo
is intended for accumulating wealth
or saving for various purposes.
Provides annual cash payment benefits
and end-of-term benefits
with values ​​depending on the
payment period, coverage period, and
premium amount.
Coverage period 10, 15, 20, and 30
years.
Annual cash payment benefits are
provided starting from the end of the first year
for a lump sum premium or starting from the end of the
fifth year for a 5-year MPP or
starting from the end of the 10th year for a 10-
year MPP and so on every year until
the end of the selected coverage period.
This is a table of
annual cash payment benefits for a
10-year coverage period.  Please take a look.
Then this is the annual cash payment benefit
for a coverage period of 15
years.
Next is the annual cash payment benefit
for a 20-year coverage period
and this one is for a 30-year coverage period
.
Then the
final benefit for a
10-year coverage period, the
15-year coverage period.
Final benefit for 20 years coverage period
and final benefit for
30 years coverage period.  No need to
memorize it, there will be illustrations later.
Basic insurance benefits.  So this product
has insurance benefits, namely if
the insured dies due to an
accident, the EDB accidental death benefit
or experiences permanent total disability
.  TPD total permanent disability
will be given an additional annual cash value
every year from the incident
until the end of the coverage period.   The
first payment is given after the
ADB or TPD claim is approved and
thereafter benefits are given together
with annual cash payments.  Except
for scholarship clients, yes.  He has no
annual cash payment benefits.
If ADB or TPD occurs during the
payment period, all benefits are provided
pro rata, including ADB or
TPD benefits, annual payment benefits, and
end-of-coverage benefits.
This is the MDWA basic insurance benefits table
applicable to all plans and
currencies.  For the lump sum premise payment period
, the benefit is 5% of the
premise at once.  For
5 years of premium payments the benefit is 25% of the
annual basic premium.  And for a
10-year premium payment period, the benefit is 50% of the
annual basic premium.  Note that the
death benefit due to an accident has no
waiting period.  However, for
total disability benefits, there is still a
12-month waiting period and the TPD condition
must last for 180 days.  TPD
can be caused by illness or
accident.  And this is the same status,
both are subject to a 12 month waiting period
.
Next are additional insurance benefits
or riders.
There is an advance life protector plus additional
life insurance money.
Two, manifest of premium plus.
Premium exemption if you experience one of 89
critical illnesses during the payment period.
Three, Manulif Benefit Plus.
Premium exemption if the premium payer
dies or becomes totally permanently disabled during the
payment period.
Here is the explanation for Advance Live
Protector Plus.
Entry age 30 days to 70 years.  The
premium payment period can be 5 years
or 10 years at once and can be different from the
premium payment for the
basic insurance product.
coverage period until the
basic coverage period ends.
Rupiah and US Dollar currencies.
Full underwriting underrating method.
This Raider can be an option for those of you who
want to provide insurance money that is
given simultaneously to heirs
because the basic MDWA product does not
provide it.  But the condition is that you must
still be healthy.
Next Manuliz Waver of Premium
Plus entry age 18 to 55 years.  The
premium payment period follows the
premium payment period for the basic insurance product
.  The coverage period follows the
premium payment period for basic insurance products and
only applies to the
premium payment period in
Rupiah and US Dollars.
Full underwriting method.
This table lists the critical illnesses
covered by this raider.  Please just
look,
there are 89 of them.  Then manifest prior benefit
plus entry age 18 to 70 years.  The
premium payment period follows the
premium payment period for the basic insurance product
.  The coverage period follows the
premium payment period for basic insurance products and
only applies to
premium payment periods of 5 and 10 years.
Rupiah and US dollar currencies.
Full underwriting underrating method.
This benefit can be taken only if the
premium payer is different from the
insured.  For example, the premium payer is
the father and the insured child or the
premium payer is the husband and the insured wife
.
The following is an illustration of an MDWA
annuity plan for rupiah currency and a
lump sum premium.  Here I will give an example with a
premium of R500 million at once.  Starting from the end of the
sixth year, you will receive an annual cash benefit of IDR
47,500,000
every year until the end of the 19th year.
At the end of the 20th year, he got R7.5 million.
So in the end, this is different, right?   The
total benefit is Rp. 742.5.
R500,000 or there is a profit of
R242,500,000.
On average, the profit is
2.43% per year.  Then there are ADB
or TPD benefits in the form of additional
cash compensation of 25 million per year from the year of the
incident until the end of the
coverage period.  For example, if you
die due to an accident in the
fourth year, then in the fourth year you will
receive 25 million every year until the end of the
20th year.  and in the sixth year and
beyond still receive 47.5 million.  This is
an example of an MDWA
annuity illustration for the rupiah currency with a
5-year payment period.  Here I give
an example with a premium of millions per year.
So the first year is R00 million, the second year is
R00 million, until the fifth year is R00 million.
The total is R500 million.  Then you will get
annual cash benefits starting from the end of the
10th year amounting to IDR 65 million until the end of the
19th year.  So, in the 20th year,
he received Rp. 95 million.  The total benefit is
IDR 745 million or there is a profit of IDR 245
million.  On average, the profit is
IDR 2.45%
per year.  The benefits of ADB TPD are the same, yes.
Next is an illustration of MDWA annuity for
US Dollar currency with lump sum premium.
Here I will give an example with a premium of 000,
so starting from the end of the sixth year you will
receive 4,125
US until the 19th year.  And in the
20th year you will receive 5,625
US.  Total received 63,375 375 US
or there is a profit of 1,375.
On average, the profit is 1.34%
per year.  As for the
ADBTPD benefits, they are an additional
cash benefit of 2,500 per year from the year of the
incident until the end of the
coverage period.  Then this is an illustration of
MDWA annuity with US Dollar currency
premium for 5 years.  Here I give an example of a
premium of 10,000,000 US per year for
5 years.  Total deposit 50,000.   The
annual cash benefit can be seen
here and it has an average profit of 1.2%
per year.
Next illustration of MDWA scholarship in
rupiah currency at once premise.  Here's an example:
if the premium is IDR 500 million, then at the end of the
20th year it will be IDR 1.30 million
or there will be a profit of IDR 30 million.  On
average, the profit is 5.3%
per year.  The benefits of ADBTPD are the same.
Then this is an illustration of the MDWA
5-year rupiah currency scholarship.  Premises of R million
for 5 years total R500 million.  So at
the end of the 20th year it will be 980 million
or there will be an average profit of 4.8% per
year.  If you calculate the compound interest,
it's around 3.5%.  Next,
I will illustrate the MDWA scholarship in US Dollar currency
with a premium of 0,000,
so after 20 years it will become
81,000.
average profit of 3.15% per year.
Next is an illustration of the MDWA
5-year US Dollar currency scholarship.  The premium is
IDR 10,000 per year for 5 years, so
at the end of the 20th year it will be IDR
71,500.
Next illustration MDWA Combo
rupiah currency premises at once.  Here
I will give an example with a one-time premium of IDR 500 million
.  So the benefit is that there is an
annual cash benefit given
starting from the end of the first year of R10
million every year until the end of the
20th year.  The total annual cash benefit is
R200 million and at the end of the 20th year will
receive another R5 million.  So there is a
total profit of R5 million.  On average, the
profit is 4.05% per year.
Next is an illustration of MDWA Combo with
rupiah currency and a 5-year payment period
.  Here is an example of a premise of R million
per year for 5 years.  So
the benefit starting at the end of the fifth year will be
to receive R million every year until
the end of the 20th year.  And at the end of the
20th year will receive another R540 million.  There is a
profit of Rp. 360 million if the average
is 3.6% per year.
Then here is an illustration of the MDWA combo
US Dollar currency premium at the same time here.
For example, the premium,
then the annual cash benefit is
500 US every year from the end of the
first year until the end of the 20th year.  And at
the end of the 20th year will receive another
61,500.
There is a profit of 21,500
or an average of 2.15% per year.
Next, here is an illustration of the MDWA combo
US Dollar currency with a 5-
year premium.  For example, the annual premium for 5
years totals 000,
then starting at the end of the fifth year you will
receive an annual cash benefit
of 11,100 US every year until the
end of the 20th year.  And at the end of the
20th year you will receive another 51,500
US.  There is a profit of 19,100
US, yes.  On average, the profit is 1.91%
per year.  All these benefits are
guaranteed and tax-free.
Furthermore, this claim method is
very easy.  There is a claim for
annual cash payment benefits.  Just
fill out the payment form for
insurance benefits, stages or dividends, and a
photocopy of your identity card.  Send to email
customerserviceid@manulif.com.
As for end-of-term benefit claims
, fill out the
end-of-contract or maturity benefit payment form
, attach your ID card or passport, and
send it to
customerserviceid@manulif.com.
Then, for death benefit claims,
please just read it.  And this is a
flawed claim.  All forms can be downloaded on the
Manulif website.
Next is how to register.  Please
ask for an MDWA proposal to be made.  Then, if it's
okay, you can meet with my agent
to fill out the SPAJ,
life insurance application letter, prepared attachments,
KTP, proof of transfer, premium payment,
and other supporting documents if
needed.  Then wait for the
underrating process.  You will be
notified if the policy is approved or
additional information is required.  But this is a
policy guarantee that is approved, unless there is a
rider.
Next, thank you, I am Asep
Sofyan, Manu Live agent.  This is my contact
08211650732.
I have a blog asuransihiu.com.  Please
visit to get information
about Manulif products including
MDWA.  That's all I can
say about MDWA products.  Hopefully, this will
be useful for those of you who are
looking for savings or
investment instruments with guaranteed and
certain returns that are tax-free.  See you in the
next video.